

PO BOX 2754, Snowflake, Arizona 85937, (928) 243-4522, SHANEHANCOCK64@LIVE.COM

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Strong background in industrial operations and maintenance with an educational background in software engineering and also courses in O&M. In operations i have worked with a variety of heavy equipment to control room operations with SCADA systems. Proficient in MS Office, Javascript, SQL, NODE, and experience with other programs and languages. I complete my Software Engineering Certification from the University of Arizona in August, 2022.

SKILLS

- Time management, Decision making,
 HTML, CSS, Bootstrap
 MS Office

 Problem solving, Trouble Shooting
- SQL, MySQL, MondoDB
- JavaScript, jQuery, React.js, Node.js, Express.js,

EXPERIENCE

Safety Team Member April 2022 - Current
BNSF Railway | Winslow , AZ

- Conduct various safety audits, safety briefings, field discussions, and other safety related activities per Local
- · Leadership and the Safety Team Leader guidance.
- Work closely with Local Leadership, the Safety Team Leader, along with other Safety Team Members and employees to resolve any barriers to safe work and keeping safety culture moving in a positive direction.
- Assist in oversight, lead In-Field Training and Re-Training
 Process with involvement of Local Leaders, Team Leader, Team
 Members and others to create an educational plan to address the at-risk behavior. Assist in the development of appropriate action plans, analyze trends and create a communication strategy to educate the workforce in-order to reduce the risk and likelihood of reoccurrence. This includes looking for ways to improve and/or streamline the process to maximize the impact.
- Schedule/Coordinate Safety Team Meetings and be prepared for each meeting using appropriate agenda, providing a recap of action items in absence of the Safety Team Leader.

BNSF Railway | Winslow, AZ

- Knowledgeable of all railroad operating and safety rules such as GCOR, Hours of service laws, Air brake and train handling, TYE safety rules, US Hazardous material instructions for rail, System special instructions, Timetables etc
- · Proper radio communication
- · Blue signal protection
- · Safe and efficient operation of trains and cars
- · FRA certified Conductor
- Working on call 24/7
- · Making up of trains while staying in compliance
- · Handling of Hazmat materials
- · Operating switches and Derails
- Knowledge of airbrake systems
- Trouble shooting broken down trains
- · Working responsibly in an unsupervised locations
- Copying mandatory directives from dispatchers
- Preparing all paper work before departure
- Perform pre-job safety briefings before attempting work following up with a debrief.

CONCENTRATOR OPERATOR

October 2012 - January 2013

Freeport-McMoRan | Morenci, AZ

- Responsible for extraction of copper after the crushing and milling process before going to tailings
- · Monitoring plant systems from a control room
- · Making routine checks through the plant while taking samples
- Checking samples and preparing them to be sent off to the lab
- Sampling and maintaining proper PH levels using lime
- Running pumps, float banks, dysters, and electric motors
- Troubleshooting when there's a plant failure and following proper procedures to repair it
- Taking equipment on and off line for scheduled maintenance
- Operating valves with Pneumatic actuators and by hand
- Following MSHA rules and using proper PPE
- · Working shift work
- · Using radios for communication.

OPERATOR

April 2012 - September 2012

Catalyst Paper Mill | Snowflake, AZ

- Proficient operation on cranes ranging from 1 Ton to 50 Ton
- Maintaining chemicals for paper machines
- Operating machines to cut cores for paper spools
- · Operating forklifts

- · Unloading delivery trucks
- · Practiced the use of Lock out Tag out
- · Working on outages changing felts, wires, taking machines off line, and using proper start up procedures
- · Pumping chemicals from railcars
- Working shift work.

SHOP ASSISTANT June 2009 - April 2012

Showlow Construction Taylor | AZ

- · Inspected equipment for defects and damage
- · Performed maintenance such as oil changes, greasing, air filters, tire changes, etc
- · Cleaned all equipment coming off jobsites to pass DOT inspections
- · Operated heavy equipment such as; forklifts, telescoping forklifts, backhoes, loaders, excavators, dozers, etc
- Performed industrial housekeeping duties keeping the shop free from hazards
- Organized and labeled shop inventory
- · Keeping inventory updated and stocked regularly
- Practiced the use of PPE and following OSHA rules
- Assisted with loading/unloading of equipment onto lowboy trailers
- · Assisted shop mechanic while gaining a basic knowledge of diesel engines, hydraulics, and troubleshooting.

LABORER June 2007 - August 2007

Western Grade | AZ

- Cleaned and prepared job sites
- · Controlled traffic on and near job sites
- · Loaded and unload job materials
- Assisted heavy equipment operators
- Gained knowledge in an industrial environment while practicing proper safety procedures.

EDUCATION

Software Engineering Coding Bootcamp

August 2022

University of Arizona, Tucson, Arizona

Full stack coding bootcamp including; HTML, CSS, Javascript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Node.js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express.js, React.js.

Industrial Operations and Maintenance

August 2011

Northland Pioneer Community college, Snowflake, AZ